A Guide to the Staige D. Blackford Papers
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- O. S. Certificate from the Jefferson Literary Society and from the Charlottesville Public Schools, 2 items
- 1985-1986 College admission letters, 6 items (Box-folder 10:2)
  There are letters written by Staige Blackford regarding information about colleges for his daughter, Linda Blackford
- 1969-1993 Employment, 42 items (Box-folder 10:3)
  There is correspondence about his position at the University including letters from University of Virginia Presidents Robert O' Neil and John Casteen about faculty status and salary. There are also resumes of Staige Blackford
- 1945; 1989 Episcopal High School, 2 items (Box-folder 10:4)
  There is a bill for books and a list of expenses. Also included is an article about Dr. Blackford's diary being available in the School Library
- 1954-1988 Financial Papers, 28 items (Box-folder 10:5)
  There are financial papers for their house on Westview Road, from Staige's mother's estate, and other bills and credit information.
- 1989-2003 Financial Papers, 50 items (Box-folder 10:6)
  Included is a draft of Staige Blackford's will and last testament
- n. d. Genealogy, 4 items (Box-folder 10:7)
  There is a genealogical chart, a brief history of Dr. Staige Blackford (1898-1949) and an autobiography of Dr. Staige Blackford that was written in a letter to Staige.
- 1998-2000 Governor's Awards to the Fine Arts, 1 item (Box-folder 10:8)
  There is information about Wolf trap and nominees for the awards
- 1945-1950 Grades, 40 items (Box-folder 10:9)
  There are grades for Staige Blackford from Episcopal High School and the University of Virginia. There is also an aptitude test for Linda Blackford; and a bill for tuition at EPS (1916)
- 1991-1992 Health Care Reform, 8 items (Box-folder 10:10)
  There is correspondence with William McClatchey about health care reform. Staige Blackford was passionate about this issue.
- 1988-1989 History of Norfolk Symposium, 7 items (Box-folder 10:11)
  There is general correspondence about this project
- 1976-1998 Insurance Papers, 90 items (Box-folder 10:12)
- 1991 Insurance and Automobile accident, 20 items (Box-folder 10:13)
  Bettina was involved in an automobile accident when a large truck hit her car and seriously impaired her physical mobility. Her employment was also affected as her ability to teach and ride horses became limited
- 1969 Itineraries, 6 items (Box-folder 11:1)
  There are daily schedules for Linwood Holton for September and October
- n. d. "Manuscript Mine Eyes Have Seen the Glory", 1 item (Box-folder 11:2)
  Launcelot Minor Blackford manuscript
- n. d. Miscellaneous, 11 items (Box-folder 11:3)
  Included are two packages of dental poultice from the medical department of the U. S. Navy; and some miscellaneous school signatures, stories and drawings
- 2000-2003 Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 20 items (Box-folder 11:4)
  Various newsclippings on unrelated topics
- 1951; 1960; 1992; 1998; 2003 Obituaries, 23 items (Box-folder 11:5)
  Obituaries for Dan S. Norton, Henry N. Taylor, and Jonathan Hughes. Also included is a speech from the memorial service of Staige Blackford
- n.d. Photographs, 52 items (Box-folder 11:6)
- O. S. Holsinger photograph 1924 UVA football team, 1 item
- O. S. Photograph of Mary B. Blackford (1802-1895) and William Blackford (1801-1864), 1 item
- 1965; 1968; 1990 Political campaigns, 8 items (Box-folder 11:7)
  Poll results, agendas, and speech notes
- 1951-1954 Rhodes Scholarship, 50 items (Box-folder 11:8)
  correspondence, syllabus, and receipts
- 1989; 1993 Rhodes Scholars Reunion, 8 items (Box-folder 11:9)
- 1985; 1989; 1990; 1993 South Atlantic Modern Language Association, 32 items (Box-folder 11:10)
- 1995 Speech at Emory: One Man's South, 21 items (Box-folder 11:11)
- 1985; n. d. Speeches, 6 items (Box-folder 11:12)
- 1969-1974 Speeches of Linwood Holton and others, 25 items (Box-folder 12:1)
  Included are prepared remarks of Linwood Holton at the Clergy Association of the Richmond Area; Testimonial Dinner for Lewis F. Powell, Jr., Carillon Civic Association; Old Dominion University Commencement; Omicron Delta Kappa Chapter at Washington and Lee; Veterans Day War Memorial in Richmond; Republican National Committee; Ripon Society Banquet; Virginia Military Institute Commencement; Virginia Chapter of American Association of University Professors; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University Commencement; University of Virginia Student Legal Forum; Lee Family at Stratford Hall; Rotary Convention; National Conference of Editorial Writers. Also included are speeches by The Reverend John S. Spong about Vietnam and John Osman at the Brookings Institute. There is also a summary of the Linwood Holton years.
- 1956; 1964; n. d. Subscription orders, 5 items (Box-folder 12:2)
  There are renewal forms for subscriptions to various magazines
- 1950-1953 Travel, 23 items (Box-folder 12:3)
  Various maps and travel information as well as correspondence about traveling in Europe
- 1955-1957 United States Air Force, 25 items (Box-folder 12:4)
  Papers relating to the Air Force including Staige's honorable discharge
- 1959; 1990 University of Virginia, 3 items (Box-folder 12:5)
  There are articles about the University and an annual report summary written by Robert O'Neil
- 1989 UVA Clubhouse, 3 items (Box-folder 12:6)
- n. d. Virginia Quarterly Review, 1 item (Box-folder 12:7)
  Anthology of the VQR
- Restricted
  - 1989 Student assignments: Graded papers for ENWR 370 and 301 Confidential, 10 papers (Box 13)
    Access to diaries requires written permission from Blackford's daughters through the year 2034.
  - Staige Blackford Diaries, 13 diaries (Box 13)
    1980 January-May
    1980 May-September
    1980 October-1981 February
    1981 August-1982 January 3
    1982 January-June
    1982 June-October
    1982 October-December, 1983 January-March
    1983 March-August
    2001 March 29-July
    2001 July 18- November 29
    2001 November 30-2002 August
    2002 August-2003 January
    2003 January-June 9